Guide to the Fritz Reiner papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Fritz Reiner Papers,
1916-1983
Reiner, Fritz, 1888-1963.
0.5 linear ft. (ca.100 items in 1 box).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027
4079910
Biographical Note
Reiner was born in Budapest in 1888. He graduated from the Budapest Academy of Music in 1908 where he studied with Bela Bartok. Various conducting and directing appointments followed in Budapest and in Dresden, including that of chief conductor of the Royal Opera House in Dresden for 1914-1922. An acquaintance of Richard Strauss, Reiner was influenced by conductor Arthur Nikisch and Hungarian composer Leo Weiner. In 1922 Reiner left Europe to become the appointed director of the Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra, a post he held until 1930. In 1928 he became an American citizen. He married his second wife, Cincinnati actress Carlotta Irwin, in 1930.
From 1931-1941 Reiner served as head of the orchestra and opera departments at the Curtis Institute of Music, where Leonard Bernstein was his student. He supervised activities of the Philadelphia Academy of Music and was a frequent guest conductor at the Philadelphia Grand Opera. During that time he also participated in opera festivities at Covent Gargen in honor of King Edward VIII's coronation and Wagner performances at the San Francisco Opera from 1936-1938.
In 1938 Reiner was appointed conductor and music director of the Pittsburgh Symphony, resigning in 1948 over financial disputes. He became conductor at the Metropolitan Opera in New York City where he debuted with an historic performance of Strauss' Salome on February 4 1949. Among the 113 performances conducted during that brief tenure were acclaimed performances of Tristan und Isolde and Der Rosenkavalier and the organization's premiere of Stravinsky's The Rake's Progress.
From 1953-1962 Reiner conducted the Chicago Symphony. He died in New York City on November 15 1963.
Scope and Content
Letters, notes, programs, photographs, and printed materials. The collection is comprised primarily of handwritten correspondence between Reiner and notable music figures including Samuel Barber, Leonard Bernstein, Aaron Copland, Lukas Foss, Darius Milhaud, Arthur Nikisch. Arnold Schoenberg, Richard Strauss, Igor Stravinsky, and Leo Weiner. Also of note, letters from writer and conductor Gian Francesco Milpiero and his wife Auna detailing wartime conditions in Italy (1946).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 1 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Subjects
American Youth for Democracy.; New York Philharmonic.; Pittsburgh Symphony Orchestra; Babin, Victor, 1908-1972.; Barber, Samuel, 1910-; Bartók, Béla, 1881-1945.; Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-; Casella, Alfredo, 1883-1947.; Copland, Aaron, 1900-; Dent, Edward Joseph, 1876-1957.; Foss, Lukas, 1922-; Godowsky, Leopold, 1870-1938.; Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974.; Nikisch, Arthur, 1855-1922.; Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951.; Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949.; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971.; Weiner, Leó, 1885-1960.; Wobisch, Helmut, 1912-1980.; Music--20th century.; Music--New York--20th century.; Operas--20th century.; Orchestral music.; Notes.; Photographs.; Programs.; Conductors.; Musicians.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
2001 M-2001 Papers Reiner, Carlotta Gift/Transfer from Music Library
Gift of Carlotta Reiner.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Barber, Sam To Fritz Reiner, Mount Kisco, NY, 15 August [n.d.], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    [Thank you note]
  - Bartok, Bela To Fritz Reiner., New York, NY, 27 June 1942, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    [With postmarked envelope and unsigned acknowledgement form.]
  - Bartok, Bela To Fritz Reiner, Bronx, NY, 11 Sept. 1942, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    [With envelope.]
  - Bernstein, Leonard To Fritz Reiner, New York, NY, [n.d.], (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    [Emotional personal announcement of Bernstein's appointment as assistant conductor of NY Philharmonic. Stationery: M. Witmark & Sons, Publishers, NY.]
  - Bernstein, Leonard To "Uncle Fritz" [Fritz Reiner], New York, NY, 9 February 1944 (postmark), (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    [Stationery: The Philharmonic-Symphony Society of New York. With envelope. ]
  - Bernstein, Shirley To Mrs. Reiner, New York, NY, 5 February 1944, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    [Thank you note on stationery: The Philharmonic Symphony Society of New York.]
  - Bernstein, Samuel To Fritz Reiner, Boston, MA, 4 February 1944, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    [Thank you note on stationary: Samuel Bernstein Hair Company.]
  - Casella, Alfredo To Fritz Reiner, Rome, Italy, 1 November 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    [In Italian. With envelope]
  - Casella, Alfredo To Fritz Reiner, Rome, Italy, 1 April 1941, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    [In Italian. With unposted envelope.]
  - Casella, Alfredo To Fritz Reiner, Rome, Italy, 10 January 1945, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    [. In Italian. With unposted envelope.]
  - Casella, Alfredo To Fritz Reiner, Rome, Italy, 20 September 1945 & 21 August 1945, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    [ In Italian.With envelope postmarked NY, NY: 5 September 45]
  - Casella, Alfredo To Fritz Reiner, Rome, Italy, 20 April 1946, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    [In Italian. With postmarked envelope.]
  - Copland, Aaron To Fritz Reiner, Bernardsville, NJ, 18 April 1940, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    [Copland appeals to Reiner to "try out" his then new work, "Danzon Cubano" with Sunday Philharmonic concerts.]
  - Dent, Edward To Fritz Reiner, Paris, France, 18 December 1936, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    [On stationary: Hotel Majestic, Paris.]
  - Foss, Lukas To Fritz Reiner, Boston, MA, October [n.d.], (2 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Foss, Lukas To Fritz Reiner, Haverford, PA, 9 September 1943, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    [References to collaboration with Robert Shaw.]
  - Foss, Lukas To Fritz Reiner, Haverford, PA, 25 September 1943, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Foss, Lukas To Fritz Reiner, Peterborough, NH, 3 January 1944, (3 pages [note sized] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    [Includes the composer's detailed description of an unfinished work (an "unborn child").]
  - Foss, Lukas To Fritz Reiner, New York City, NY, 19 February 1944, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 19)
    [Request for recommendation replacing Leonard Bernstein, NY Philharmonic. References to Bernstein and Robert Shaw.]
  - Foss, Lukas To Fritz Reiner, New York City, NY, 26 February 1944, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    [ Regarding NY Philharmonic recommendation and pianist position for the Boston Symphony Orchestra. References to Koussevitsky.]
  - Foss, Lukas To Fritz Reiner, Monterey, MA, 27 July 1944, (4 pages [note size] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    [ References to new work expanded into a symphony.]
  - Foss, Lukas To Fritz Reiner, Peterborough, NH, 27 August 1944, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    [ Agreement to present new work followed by travel arrangements.]
  - Foss, Lukas. To Mrs. Reiner, Boston, MA, 9 September 1944, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    [Travel arrangements, references to Boston Symphony Orchestra.]
  - Foss, Lukas To Fritz Reiner, Boston, MA, 22 October 1944, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    [ Regarding changes and publishing of new symphony. With posted envelope.]
  - Foss, Lukas To Fritz Reiner, Boston, MA, 25 November 1944, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    [ Completion of last movement of 226 page new symphony.]
  - Foss, Lukas To Fritz Reiner, Boston, MA, 3 April 1945, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    [Regarding new community orchestra: American Youth for Democracy.]
  - Foss, Lukas. To Fritz Reiner, Boston, MA, 5 April 1945, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 27)
    [Regarding American Youth for Democracy.]
  - Foss, Lukas To Fritz Reiner, Boston, MA, April 1945, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 28)
    [Regarding performance of new symphony. References to Koussevitsky. With posted envelope.]
  - Godowsky, Leopold Programs and menus, Astor Hotel, 13 February 1935, (2 booklets, 4 pages bd.) (Box 1, Folder 29)
    ["Surprise Dinner to the Master Leopold Godowsky," 65th anniversary. ]
  - Godowsky, Leopold To Mrs. Reiner, New York, NY, 3 March 1935, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 30)
    [Acceptance of dinner invitation.]
  - Godowsky, Leopold. To Mrs. Reiner, New York, NY, 12 March 1935, (1 page [note sized] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 31)
    [Returned performance ticket. With posted envelope.]
  - Godowsky, Leopold To Mrs. Reiner, New York, NY, 24 April 1935, (2 pages [note sized] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 32)
    [ Returned performance tickets. With posted envelope.]
  - Kingsley, Myra Fritz Reiner astrological chart, New York City, NY; Cincinnatti, OH, 22 February 1930, (7 pages t.ms.s., 1 page a.l.s. (copy) (Box 1, Folder 33)
    [On Kingsley stationery (NY) in Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra envelope. With note from Otto Klemperer.]
  - Malipiero, Gian Francesco To Fritz Reiner. Padova, Italy, 23 November 1929 [postmark], (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 34)
    [With posted envelope.]
  - Malipiero, Gian Francesco To Fritz Reiner, Asolo, Italy, 10 December 1929, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Malipiero, Gian Francesco. To Fritz Reiner, Asolo, Italy, 13 July 1932 [postmark], (2 pages a.l.s., 1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 36)
    [With note from Sgra. Malpiero to Mrs. Reiner. With posted envelope.]
  - Malipiero, Gian Francesco To Fritz Reiner, Asolo, Italy, 30 July 1932, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Malipiero, Gian Francesco To Fritz Reiner, Asolo, Italy, 3 August 1932, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Malipiero, Auna (Mrs. Gian Francesco) To Carlotta Reiner, Asolo, Italy, 15 August 1932, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Malipiero, Gian Francesco To Fritz Reiner, Asolo, Italy, 20 August 1932, (2 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Malipiero, Gian Francesco To Fritz Reiner, Asolo, Italy, 24 August 1932, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Malipiero, Gian Francesco To Fritz Riener, Asolo, Italy, 21 September 1932, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Malipiero, Gian Francesco To Fritz Reiner, Asolo, Italy, 22 October 1932, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 43)
    [With envelope postdated 15 October 1932.]
  - Malipiero, Gian Fransesco To Fritz Reiner, Asolo, Italy, 2 November 1932, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Malipiero, Auna (Mrs. Gian Francesco) To Carlotta Reiner, Venice, Italy, 17 May 1946 [postmark], (4 pages [note sized] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 45)
    [Reference to postwar conditions and request for provisions from Reiners to Malipieros. With posted envelope.]
  - The New York Times Obituary of Gian Francesco Malipiero. New York, August 2 [n.d.], (1 page newspaper clipping) (Box 1, Folder 46)
    [Death in Treviso, Italy.]
  - Milhaud, Darius To Fritz Reiner, Oakland, California, 10 October [n.d.], (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 47)
    [Stationery: Mills College.]
  - Milhaud, Darius To Fritz Reiner, Paris, 13 October [n.d.], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 48)
    [ In French.]
  - Milhaud, Darius To Fritz Reiner, Oakland, CA, [n.d.], (1 page [note sized] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 49)
    [Response to Reiner. Stationery: Mills College.]
  - Milhaud, Darius To Fritz Reiner, California, [n.d.], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 50)
    [In French. Stationery: Mills College.]
  - Babin, Victor To Fritz Reiner, New York, NY, 6 January 1942, (1 page [note sized] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 51)
    [Request to play Milhaud concerto for two pianos with handwriting on the back possibly response from Reiner. Reference to Vronsky.]
  - Babin, Victor To Fritz Reiner, New York City, NY, 16 January 1942, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 52)
    [Regarding Milhaud concerto.]
  - Milhaud, Darius To Fritz Reiner, Mills College, CA, 6 October 1942, (1 page t.l.) (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Milhaud, Darius To Fritz Reiner, Mills College, CA, 19 November 1942 [postmark], (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 54)
    [Letter of gratitude for performing his work. With posted envelope.]
  - Milhaud, Darius To Fritz Reiner, Oakland, California, 2 December 1942 [postmark], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Milhaud, Darius To Fritz Reiner, Oakland, CA., 13 November 1952, (1 page Western Union telegram) (Box 1, Folder 56)
    [Apologies for inability to attend concert. Reference to Babin and Vronsky.]
  - "The Voice of the Opera": Chicago Civic Opera Company., Chicago, IL, 12 January 1930, (4 pages bd.) (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Nikisch, Gretchen To Fritz Reiner, Liepzig, Germany, 19 April 1949, (8 pages [note sized] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Nikisch, Gretchen To Fritz Steiner, Leipzig, Germany, 21 April 1949, (4 pages [note sized] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 59)
    [With note from Arthur Nikisch and posted envelope.]
  - Nikisch, Gretchen To Carlotta Reiner, Leipzig, Germany, 25 April 1949, (2 pages [note sized] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Nikisch, Gretchen To Fritz Reiner, Leipzig, Germany, 29 June 1949, (4 pages [note sized] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Reiner, Fritz To Arnold Schoenberg. [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold To Fritz Reiner, New York City, NY, 24 May 1934 [postmark], (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold To Fritz Reiner, Los Angeles, CA, 15 July 1944, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Reiner, Fritz To Schoenberg, Arnold, Pittsburgh, PA, 27 January 1945, (1 page t.l.) (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Singanglia, Leone To Fritz Reiner, Milan, Italy, 1 June 1940, (1 page [note size] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Strauss, Richard To Fritz Reiner, Garmisch, Germany, 14 November 1930, (3 pages [note size] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Strauss, Richard To Fritz Reiner, Garmisch, Germany, 6 June 1931, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Strauss, Richard To Fritz Reiner, Garmisch, Germany, 17 November 1931, (1 page [note sized] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Strauss, Richard To Fritz Reiner, Garmisch, Germany, 10 December 1934, (2 pages [note size] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Strauss, Richard To Fritz Reiner, Garmisch, Germany, 17 November 1938, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Strauss, Richard To Fritz Steiner, Montreux, Switzerland, 19 October 1948, (2 pages [note size] a.l.s., 6 1/2 x 4 1/2 inches photograph, s.) (Box 1, Folder 72)
    [On Montreux Palace stationery with posted envelope.]
  - Strauss, Richard To Fritz Reiner, Montreux, Switzerland, 9 February 1949, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Strauss, Richard Letters and telegrams from Fritz Reiner to Strauss., [v.p.], [n.d.]; 3 April 1917; 22 June 1918; 11 February 1919; 27 March 1919; 7 July 1919; 2 November 1930; 5 June 1931; 19 October 1948, (17 pages ) (Box 1, Folder 74)
    [ Copies faxed from newphew of Richard Strauss. ]
  - Stravinsky, Igor To Fritz Reiner, Hollywood, California, 31 January 1943, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 75)
    [With postmarked envelope.]
  - Swift, Charles and Marie To Fritz Reiner, Chicago, Illinois, 9 January 1930 [postmark], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Weiner, Leo To Fritz Reiner, [n.p.], 8 November 1945, (2 pages t.l.s. and a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 77)
    [Stationery: Rozsavolgy & Tarsa, Budapest, Hungary.]
  - Weiner, Leo To Fritz Reiner, Budapest, Hungary, 14 June 1946, (4 pages [note sized] a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Wo bisch, Professor Helmut Weiner Philharmonic To Fritz Reiner, Weiner, 1 page, (t.l.s. ) (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Zirato, Bruno To Mr. Specter [no identified first name], [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 page t.l.s. and a.l.) (Box 1, Folder 80)
    [With handwritten note, possibly to Reiner. Regarding Pittsburgh Orchestra business.]
  - Zirato, Bruno To Fritz Reiner, New York, NY, 12 January 1945, (1 page Western Union telegram) (Box 1, Folder 81)
    [ Regarding Pittsburgh Orchestra business: conductor's vacation time.]
  - Mandolini, Jean-do To Rare Book and Manuscript Library. Columbia University, Paris, France, 21 February 1989, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Rare Book and Manuscript Library. Columbia University To Professor Chou Wen-chung, New York, NY, 17 April 1989, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 83)
    [Regarding remarks by Jean-do Mondolini.]
  - Fritz Reiner Society Discography of Fritz Reiner. Bound book includes printed photographs and biographical notes, 1978, (81 pages bd.) (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Black and white photograph of two unidentified men, [n.p.], [n.d.], (7 inches x 5 inches photograph) (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Chicago Symphony Orchestra Subscription concert program, Chicago, IL, 1953-1963, (87 pages t.l.) (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Mondolini, Jean-do Programs, clippings, and correspondence regarding F. Reiner., [v.p.], [n.d.] 1916-1988, (16 pages) (Box 1, Folder 87)
    [With envelope dated 24 February 1989]
  - Estate of Carlotta Reiner To School of the Arts. Columbia University, Brunswick, ME, 14 September 1983, (1 page t.l.) (Box 1, Folder 88)
    [ Regarding contents of collection to be archived.]
- Series II: Compact Disks
  - Prokofiev. Lt. Kije Suite, Op. 60 (Box 1, Folder 0023)
  - Shostakovich. Symphony No. 6 in B, Op. 53 (Box 1, Folder 0023)
  - Shostakovich. Symphony No. 6 in B, Op. 53 (Box 1, Folder 0023)
  - Mussorgsky. Scenes from Boris Godunov (Box 1, Folder 0023)
  - Tchaikovsky. Symphony No. 5 in E, Op. 64 (Box 1, Folder 0023)
  - Tchaikovsky. Symphony No. 5 in E, Op. 64 (Box 1, Folder 0023)
  - Strauss. Salome (Box 1, Folder 0024)
  - Strauss. Salome (Box 1, Folder 0024)
  - Strauss. Salome (Box 1, Folder 0024)
  - Sibelius. Concerto for Violin and Orchestra (Box 1, Folder 0024)
  - Rachmaninof Prelude in G (Box 1, Folder 0024)
  - Wagner. Unknown (Box 1, Folder 0024)
  - WQXR/Schlachtmeyer. "The Listening Room"-A Tribute to Fritz Reiner (Box 1, Folder 0025)
  - Glueck. Minuet and Dance of the Blessed Spirits from Orfeo (Box 1, Folder 0026)
  - Gershwin/Bennett. Porgy and Bess-A Symphonic Picture (Box 1, Folder 0026)
  - Strauss. Der Rosenkavalier (Box 1, Folder 0027)
  - Bizet. Carmen (Box 1, Folder 0028)
  - Wagner. Die Meistersinger (Box 1, Folder 0029)
  - Wagner. Die Götterdämmerung (Box 1, Folder 0029)
  - Mozart. Don Giovanni (Box 1, Folder 0030)
  - Verdi. Falstaff (Box 1, Folder 0030 to 32)
  - Wagner. Die Meistersinger (Box 1, Folder 0033)
  - Berlioz. Le Damnation de Faust (Box 1, Folder 0033)
  - Hindemith. Mathis der Maler (Box 1, Folder 0033)
  - Wagner. Die Meistersinger (Box 1, Folder 0034)
  - Leoncavallo. Pagliacci (Box 1, Folder 0035)
  - Bizet. Carmen (Box 1, Folder 0035)
  - Leoncavallo. Pagliacci (Box 1, Folder 0035)
  - Bizet. Carmen (Box 1, Folder 0036)
  - Wagner. Die Meistersinger (Box 1, Folder 0036)
  - Strauss. Salome (Box 1, Folder 0037)
  - Rossini. Il Signor Bruschino (Box 1, Folder 0038)
  - Debussy. Iberia (Box 1, Folder 0038)
  - Ravel. La Valse (Box 1, Folder 0038)
  - Brahms. Schicksalslied, Op. 53 (Box 1, Folder 0038)
  - Rachmaninof Rhapsody on a Theme of Paganini, Op. 43 (Box 1, Folder 0038)
  - Bach/Respighi. Pasacaglia and Fuge in C Minor (Box 1, Folder 0038)
  - Wagner. Tristan and Isolde (Box 1, Folder 0038)
  - Strauss. Elektra (Box 2, Folder 0039)
  - Strauss. Elektra (Box 2, Folder 0040)
  - Strauss. Elektra (Box 2, Folder 0041)
  - Ravel. La Valse (Box 2, Folder 0041)
  - Rimsky-Korsakov. Antar Symphony (Box 2, Folder 0041)
  - Rimsky-Korsakov. Sadko (symphonic poem) (Box 2, Folder 0041)
  - Strauss. Elektra (Box 2, Folder 0042)
  - Hindemith. Concert Music for Strings and Brass (Box 2, Folder 0043)
  - Seymour Raven. Interview of Hindemith (Box 2, Folder 0043)
  - Anton Bruckner. Symphony No. 7 (Box 2, Folder 0043)
  - Brahms. Academic Festival Overture (Box 2, Folder 0043)
  - Bach. Brandenburg Concerto No. 2 (Box 2, Folder 0043)
  - Mozart. Le Nozze di Figaro (Box 2, Folder 0043)
  - Riegger, Wallingford. New Dance (Box 2, Folder 0043)
  - Strauss. Rosenkavalier Suite (Box 2, Folder 0043)
  - Sibelius. En saga (Box 2, Folder 0043)
  - Hindemith. Concert Music for Strings and Brass (Box 2, Folder 0043)
  - Saint-Saens. Marche Militaire Francais (Box 2, Folder 0043)
  - Gershwin/Bennett. Porgy and Bess-A Symphonic Picture (Box 2, Folder 0044)
  - Strauss. Die Fledermaus (Box 2, Folder 0044)
  - Beethoven. Concerto in D for Violin, Op. 61 (Box 2, Folder 0045)
  - Mahler. Symphony No. 3 in D (Box 2, Folder 0045)
  - Wagner. Parsifal (Box 2, Folder 0045)
  - Beethoven. Piano Concerto No. 4 (Box 2, Folder 0046)
  - Bartok. Piano Concerto No. 1 (Box 2, Folder 0046)
  - Unknown. Unknown (Box 2, Folder 0046)
  - Mozart. Symphony No. 40 in G Minor (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Franck. Psyché and Le Chasseur Maudit (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Handel. Water Music Suite (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Handel. Concerto Grosso No. 21 in D Minor (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Handel. Xerxes (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Strauss. Gypsy Baron: Treasure Waltz (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Wagner. Die Meistersinger (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Wagner. Die Walküre (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Wagner. Lohengrin (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Wagner. Lohengrin (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Wagner. Siegfried (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Chausson. Symphony in Bb (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Saint-Saens. Concerto No. 1 for Cello and Orchestra, Op. 33 (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Dohnányi, Christoph von. Suite (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Goldmark, Carl. In Springtime Overture, Op. 36 (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Suk, Jose Fairy Tales-Folk Dance, Op. 16, No. 2 (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Dvorák, Antonín. Slavonic Dance, No. 1 in G Minor (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Gliére. Symphony No. 3 in D (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Thomas, Ambroise. Mignon (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Mozart. Symphony No. 38 in D (Prague) (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Wagner. Die Meistersinger (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Dvorák, Antonín. Carneval (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Glinka, Mikhail Ivanovich. Ruslan und Lyudmila (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Wagner and Thomas, Theo. Träume (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Saint-Saens. Danse Macabre (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Ponchielli. Danse of the Hours (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Glazunov, Aleksandr. Carnaval (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Weber, Carl Maria von. Euryanthe (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Suppé, Franz von. Poet and Peasant (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Tchaikovsky. Sleeping Beauty Waltz (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Bizet. Carmen (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Wagner. Lohengrin (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Wagner. Parsifal (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Rogers, Richard. Carousel Waltz (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Strauss. Wiener Blut (Box 2, Folder 0047)
  - Strauss. Der Rosenkavalier (Box 2, Folder 0048)
  - Strauss. Salome (Box 2, Folder 0049)
  - Strauss. Der Rosenkavalier (Box 2, Folder 0050)
  - Mozart. Figaro (Box 2, Folder 0050)
  - Monteverdi, Claudio. Orfeo (Box 2, Folder 0050)
  - Bizet. Carmen (Box 2, Folder 0050)
  - Strauss. Interview with Welitsch during a broadcast of Salome (Box 2, Folder 0050)
  - Mozart. Don Giovanni (Box 2, Folder 0050)
  - Verdi. Aida (Box 2, Folder 0050)
  - Berlioz. Le Carnival Romain (Box 2, Folder 0051)
  - Beethoven. Symphony No. 7 (Box 2, Folder 0051)
  - Berlioz. Le Corsaire (Box 2, Folder 0051)
  - Debussy. La Mer (Box 2, Folder 0051)
  - Horowitz Interviewed by Thomas Willis (Box 2, Folder 0051)
  - Bartok. The Miraculous Mandarin Suite (Box 2, Folder 0051)
  - Stravinsky. Variations (Box 2, Folder 0051)
  - Stravinsky. Petrouchka (Box 2, Folder 0051)
  - Wagner. Die Meistersinger (Box 2, Folder 0052)
  - Wagner. Die Götterdämmerung (Box 2, Folder 0052)
  - Delius, Frederick. Irmelin (Box 2, Folder 0053)
  - Tchaikovsky. Francesca da Rimini (Box 2, Folder 0053)
  - Weber, Carl Maria von. Abu Hassan (Box 2, Folder 0053)
  - Kodály, Zoltán. Peacock Variations (Box 2, Folder 0053)
  - Schumann. Manfred (Box 2, Folder 0054)